

Rubén D. Pire

Full-Stack Web Developer

rubenpire7@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

Summary

I am a full-stack web developer and React enthusiast passionate about clean and easy-to-follow code, with experience in pair programming and remote working. Fluent in several languages, frameworks, and technologies, and a team player with an optimistic personality that can boost the morale of any team.

Skills

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, SASS

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Work, Pair-Programming, Teamwork

Experience

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

July 2021 - Present

<u>OLC Re-opening Website</u> — A re-opening website for Obelisk Language Center, a Venezuelan academy of languages.

Built with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

<u>Math Magicians</u> — A calculator application built implementing the React framework with SPA dynamics.

Built with: JavaScript, React

<u>Covid Metrics</u> — An API-based website that possesses SPA dynamics. It displays statistics and information related to the COVID-19 pandemic for regions in the United Kingdom.

• Built with: JavaScript, React, Redux

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) October 2021 – Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
 Provided advice and tips on keeping the motivation to maintain longevity in the program.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance. By
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance. By encouraging the use of best practices.

Education

MICROVERSE

July 2021 - February 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.
- Won the "Collaborator of the Month" award while studying.

UNEXPO

November 2011 - December 2018

Engineering, Electricity

- Completed coursework about programming logic and algorithms.
- Completed coursework about PLC programming.
- Worked as a preparator for the signature Electrical Power Systems I, providing complimentary classes, assistance, and project reviews for 7th-semester students.